Joseph A Guzzardo

Queens, NY 11357 | 917-285-0167 | Joseph.a.guzzardo@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A passionate and experienced developer in *Javascript*, *React*, and *Ruby on Rails* with a background in Computer Science. Thrives in a team environment, working alongside other developers utilizing current industry project development practices. Adaptive learner drawn to the software engineering industry from a genuine excitement of the advancement and utilization of software technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, Javascript, JQuery, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Java, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

PlantStory - Frontend | Backend | Demo

Social media website that allows users to categorize and share their collection of plants.

- Single page frontend application built using *React* and designed with *Material-UI*.
- Utilized React Router for client-side routing as well as nested routes.
- Active Storage for photo storage in the backend.
- Created a Rails API following MVC patterns using Postgres.

FlatTube - Frontend | Backend | Demo

A full-stack web application having the same basic functionality of Youtube using live data.

- Created a single page front end utilizing React styled with React Bootstrap.
- Developed a *Rails API* backend using MVC patterns.
- Utilized Fetch and state to allow persistent User Created Playlists.
- Live database seeding of videos with detailed information using YouTube Data API.

Movie Reviews Website - Github | Demo

A full-stack web application for Movie Reviews with live movie data.

- Created a backend using Ruby on Rails, ActiveRecord, and SQLite.
- Utilized The *Movie Database API* to pull, parse, and seed data on all the most popular movies.
- Implemented user interface employing HTML with Ruby and Bootstrap for styling.

EXPERIENCE

St. John's University

Supervisor for Print Center

Queens, NY 09/2015 - 05/2019

- Trained new staff members of the software and procedures of running the print center.
- Executed 10+ orders per hour, made by students and administrators digitally and personally for print production, faxing, scanning, and editing.
- Conducted an investigation that saved the department over \$5,000.
- Prepared and processed invoicing, billing, and payments for services rendered.

Secretary for Student Government

09/2015 - 09/2019

- Received and processed requests for expense reimbursement ranging from \$100 to \$10,000+, utilizing in-house software to credit organizations and departments.
- Tracked, organized, and filed payment requests and budget requisitions.

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Manhattan, NY
02/2020 - 06/2020

St John's University

Bachelors of Science Degree in Computer Science

- 3.5 GPA
- Graduated Cum Laude

Queens, NY 05/2019